Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Penney P. Burnett Papers, 1973-1987
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Penney P. Burnett papers 1973-1987
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
10.0 linear feet Extent: 7000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Penney P. Burnett held the position of senior consultant for JWT and managed investor relations. The Penney P. Burnett Papers cover the years 1973-1987, with the bulk of material dating 1984-1986, years during which she worked for the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) as a consultant for investor relations. The collection primarily consists of memoranda, financial reports, organizational charts, surveys, marketing plans, stock exchange reports, annual meeting agendas, presentation speeches and layouts, news releases, cassette tapes of annual meetings, and newspaper and magazine articles concerning JWT. Materials pertain to investments and acquisitions made by JWT in the United States, Europe, Australia, Asia, and South Africa. The collection also includes material pertaining to JWT subsidiaries as well as other companies, including: Gray and Company; Goldman Sachs; Hill and Knowlton Inc.; Lord, Geller, Federico and Einstein (LGFE); Morgan Stanley; Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB); Paine Webber; Shearson Lehman Brothers; and Wertheim Schroder. In addition to these materials are correspondences and files relating to JWT executives including Don Johnson and Joseph O'Donnell. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00669
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until Use Copies can be made. Contact Research Services for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Penney P. Burnett Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1965 BA, Economics, Vanderbilt University
1965-1968 Security Analyst, Chase Manhattan Bank
1968-1972 Investment Analyst, Ford Foundation
1972-1979 Senior Investment Analyst, General Electric Company
1979-1981 Director and Manager of Investor Relations, Avon Products, Inc.
1981-circa 1984 Senior Consultant and Manager of Investor Relations, General Electric Company
circa 1984-1987 Senior Consultant and Manager of Investor Relations, J. Walter Thompson Company
Collection Overview
The Penney P. Burnett Papers cover the years 1973-1987, with the bulk of material dating 1984-1986, years during which she worked for the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) as a consultant for investor relations. The collection primarily consists of memoranda, financial reports, organizational charts, surveys, marketing plans, stock exchange reports, annual meeting agendas, presentation speeches and layouts, news releases, cassette tapes of annual meetings, and newspaper and magazine articles concerning JWT. Materials pertain to investments and acquisitions made by JWT in the United States, Europe, Australia, Asia, and South Africa. The collection also includes material pertaining to JWT subsidiaries as well as other companies, including: Gray and Company; Goldman Sachs; Hill and Knowlton Inc.; Lord, Geller, Federico and Einstein (LGFE); Morgan Stanley; Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB); Paine Webber; Shearson Lehman Brothers; and Wertheim Schroder. In addition to these materials are correspondences and files relating to JWT executives including Don Johnson and Joseph O'Donnell.
Collection Arrangement
The Collection is arranged into eight series: General Office Files; Meetings and Presentations; News Releases; Printed Documents; Binders and Reports; Audio Material; Plaques; and Oversize Material. General Office Documents include correspondences related to financial, organizational and planing aspects of JWT, company mergers, and company and employee stock investments both domestic and international. Also included are materials pertaining to JWT offices and subsidiaries in Europe, Great Britain, South Africa, China and Australia. Meetings and Presentations contain memoranda, reminders, agendas, presentation layouts that include slide documentation, scripts of speeches, notes and other documents relating to meetings of JWT committees, groups, managers and staff. News Releases contain statements published by JWT and subsidiary companies that involved company mergers, executives and other employees, and company quarterly reports. Printed Documents contain published material including magazine covers, articles, slides from presentations, and posters. Binders and Reports include manuals, yearly financial material, and fact books. Audio Material consist of audiocassettes of annual meetings. Plaques contains a plaque from the Pacific Stock Exchange Inc. Oversize Material contains large format items that were removed from previous series.
Subject Headings
Burnett, Penney P.; O'Donnell, Joseph W.; Johnston, Don, 1927-; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Company. New York Office; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies -- China; Advertising agencies -- South Africa; Advertising agencies -- Europe; Goldman, Sachs & Co; Morgan Stanley & Co; Hill and Knowlton, Inc.; Paine Webber Inc.; Shearson Lehman Brothers; Gray and Company; Wertheim & Co; Simmons Market Research Bureau; Subsidiary corporations; Corporations -- Investor relations; Audiocassettes; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collections within the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Harry Clark Papers
Don Johnston Papers
Samuel W. (Samuel Williams) Meek Papers
Joseph O'Donnell Papers
Jack Peters Papers
Thomas Sutton Papers
Edward G. Wilson Papers
Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department Records
London Office. Records
Contents of Collection
- General Office Documents, 1973-1987, (6 boxes)
  Includes correspondence related to financial, organizational and planing aspects of JWT, pertaining to company mergers and company and employee stock investments. Also included are files on JWT international activities in Europe, Great Britain, South Africa, China and Australia.
  - Ad Age Survey, 1984-1987, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Award, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Barrons, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Broadcasting, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Brouillard Communications, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Call reports, 1986, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - China, 1985 (Box 1)
    [Observations on economics and politics within the Republic of China on JWT companies located in Japan, Hong Kong, Beijing.]
  - JWT Chairman Letter Issues 2-4, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Competition, 1985-1986, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Distribution lists, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - EAI release, 1985 (Box 2)
    [Agreement with management of three agencies remaining in the EAI network to sell their agencies back to them and discontinue the EAI networks.]
  - Electric media updates, 1985 (Box 2)
  - JWT Europe, 1986-1986 (Box 2)
  - Europe Commercial Paper Program, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Executive committee, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Financial Fact Book, 1984 (Box 2)
  - First Manhattan Capital Management, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Germany, 1985 (Box 2)
    [Charts indicating the development of German offices in Hamburg.]
  - Gray and Company, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Golden Sachs, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Hill and Knowlton, 1985-1987, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Investment proposals, Group board of Directors, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Investment proposals, Group executive committee, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Investor relations, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Investor relations, Executive committee, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Investor relation plans, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Investor relation programs, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson annual reports, 1986 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson board of directors meeting minuets, 1986 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson Company, 1986 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson communications background, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson communication guidelines, 1973-1979, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson Group, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    [Includes research briefs and photocopied articles.]
  - J. Walter Thompson Group disclosure policy, 1981 (Box 2)
  - J. Walter Thompson stocks, 1983 (Box 3)
  - J. Walter Thompson USA, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    [Includes photocopied news paper articles, and financial reports for JWT companies within the United States.]
  - Laidlaw Adams and Peck Inc., 1985 (Box 3)
  - London Stock Exchange, 1981-1983, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Lord, Geller, Federico, Einstein, Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 3)
  - Management assessment, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Morgan Stanley, 1986 (Box 4)
  - MRB Group, 1986-1987, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Management news, 1985 (Box 4)
  - New American consumer, 1986 (Box 4)
  - New business, 1985-1987, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    [Includes book of succession of new managers, clients, account, markets, gains and losses and changes within company. Also includes photocopied news paper articles and annual reviews.]
  - New York Stock Exchange, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - O'Donnell, Joseph, 1987, (4 folders; 1 folder removed to Oversize Materials) (Box 4)
  - Offices, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Pacific Stock Exchange, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Paine Webber news letter, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Policy, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Professional Incentive Plan (PIP), 1985 (Box 5)
  - Press clippings, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Press relations, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Procedures, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Professional developments, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Shearson Lehman Brothers, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB), 1986 (Box 5)
  - Security and Exchange, 1979-1986, (1-8 of 11 folders) (Box 5)
    [Contains analyst reports, recommendations and concerns, stock reviews, memoranda, media billing break downs, notes of discussions, surveys, progress reports, industry notes, permissions requests, and brokerage reports from JWT and subsidiary companies. All previously listed items are in chronological order by year and month.]
  - Security and Exchange, 1986-1987, (continued), (9-11 of 11 folders) (Box 6)
  - South Africa, 1984-1986, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    [Includes booklet with JWT statement of principles regarding Apartheid in South Africa. Also included is a photocopy of a poster for advertising in South Africa (both poster and statement of principles are located with Oversized Material) and newspaper articles with both positive and negative reactions to advertising in South Africa during Apartheid.]
  - Stock review, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Thompson Recruitment, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Wertheim Schroder, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - Wood Gundy, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Wall Street transcripts, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
- Meetings and Presentations, 1985-1987, (3 boxes)
  Includes memoranda, reminders, agendas, presentation layouts that include slide documentation, scripts of speeches, notes and other documents relating to meetings of JWT committees, groups, managers and staff.
  - Analysts meeting, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Annual stock holders meeting, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Atlanta security analysts meeting, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Boston security analysts meeting, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Boston analysts meeting, 1984 (Box 7)
  - California meeting/presentation, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Chicago financial analysts presentation, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Gray and Company stock holders meeting, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Growing Through Leadership Presentation, 1986 (Box 8)
  - JWT annual meeting, 1986 (Box 8)
  - JWT annual meeting notice, 1980-1984 (Box 8)
  - JWT annual meeting presentation, 1984 (Box 8)
  - JWT annual stock holders meeting, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - JWT stock holders and clients meeting, 1986 (Box 8)
  - JWT New York analyst meeting, 1987 (Box 8)
  - JWT annual meeting, 1987 (Box 8)
  - New York analysts meeting, 1986 (Box 8)
  - New York City security analysts meetings, 1982-1985, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Paine Webber conference, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Paine Webber Inc. Year of Transition presentation, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Paine Webber Inc. research analysts, 1986, (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Security analyst meeting, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Wertheim breakfast, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Warner-Lambert presentation, 1985 (Box 9)
- News Releases, 1986-1987, (1 box)
  Includes statements made by JWT and subsidiary companies that involve company mergers, executives and other employees, and company quarterly reports.
  - Hill and Knowlton acquisition completion, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Hill and Knowlton merger with Carl Byoir, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Hill and Knowlton merger with Gray and Co., 1986, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Hill and Knowlton operations, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Hill and Knowlton reorganization, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT first quarter, 1986-1987, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - JWT second quarter, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT third quarter, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT Burt Manning, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT associates acquisition of Carl Byoir, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT corrects dividend, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT dividend, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - JWT earning drop, 1987 (Box 9)
  - JWT Glen A. Dell, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT and Gray and Co. amendment, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT merger with Gray and Co., 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT group reports, 1987 (Box 9)
  - JWT major international research, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT Martin Sorrell, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - JWT new directors, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT new TV guide, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT stock re-purchase, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT Terence Martin, 1986 (Box 9)
  - JWT Winona, 1986 (Box 9)
- Printed Material, 1981-1987, (1 box)
  Includes magazine covers, articles, slides from presentations, and posters.
  - Video storyboard, 1981-1984 (Box 9)
  - Hill and Knowlton directory, 1983 (Box 9)
  - New York City security analysts annual report, 1984 (Box 9)
  - JWT UK, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
  - Boston security analysts annual report, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Share holders annual meeting, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Chicago analyst meeting, 1985 (Box 10)
  - MBL Group, 1986 (Box 10)
  - JWT Europe, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - JWT flippers, 1986 (Box 10)
    [Laminated booklet on Changes in the way Americans watch TV.]
  - JWT annual report, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Hispania poster, 1986 (Box 10)
  - JWT quarterly pamphlets, 1970-1987 (Box 10)
- Reports and Binders, 1980-1986, (2 boxes)
  Series contain material that were held in large binders; includes manuals, yearly financial material,and fact books. Organized alphabetically.
  - Advertising Industry Overview, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Hill and Knowlton Source Book, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Investment Research, 1986 (Box 10)
  - JWT Files, 1980-1986, (4 folders) (Box 10)
  - JWT Financial Fact Book, 1985 (Box 10)
  - JWT Increase Effectiveness, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - JWT master list, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - JWT memos and files, 1986, (4 folders) (Box 11)
  - JWT security analysis, 1984-1985, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Prudential Bache, 1986 (Box 11)
- Audio Material, 1985-1987, (1 box)
  - Annual meeting tapes, 1985-1987, (7 audiocasssettes) (Box 12)
- Plaques, 1985, (1 box)
  - Pacific Stock Exchange plaque, 1985 (Box 13)
- Oversized Material, 1980-1987, (1 box)
  Contains large format documents, primarily posters, photo-copied new paper and magazine articles that were removed from previous series. Arrangement is in order of series.
  - Joseph O'Donnell, 1987 (Box 14)
    [Fourth folder of a four folder series. Contains photocopied news articles.]
  - South Africa, 1984-1986 (Box 14)
    [Third folder of a three folder series. Contains photocopied news articles and advertisement posters.]
  - Wall Street transcripts, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
  - Annual report poster, 1985 (Box 14)